<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Robert Franklin</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Robert Franklin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cluster Analysis of Baseball Hall of Fame ballots</title>
      <link>/post/cluster-hof-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cluster-hof-2018/</guid>
      <description>This is an analysis of how different voters vote for the baseball Hall of Fame, using cluster analysis using 2018 data.
The main motivation for this analysis is to examine patterns in voting, in order to see what kind of voters exist. I wanted to use a dataset to explore cluster analysis and try to teach myself this technique. The idea was to find a dataset where I had a hypothesis about what kind of clusters to expect, then to examine whether those clusters were there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching R with RStudio Cloud</title>
      <link>/post/teaching-r-with-rstudio-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/teaching-r-with-rstudio-cloud/</guid>
      <description>If you’re interested in using R and RStudio to teach statistics, one of the biggest issues is installing and getting started with R. I use RStudio, which is an IDE for R (basically, a shell that runs on top of R and makes it easier to use). But installing R and then installing RStudio can be a bit of a hassle.
This is where I found https://rstudio.cloud, a great way to check out what R is like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis in the Bible</title>
      <link>/post/sentiment-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sentiment-bible/</guid>
      <description>I discovered sentiment analysis a few years ago, following interesting work by Matthew Jockers and Julia Silge. Sentiment analysis is a way to compare the emotional content of text by analyzing the frequency of certain words that reflect different emotions. This could be positivity or negativity or the use of specific emotional words.
One idea I wanted to do was analyze the sentiment of the Christian Bible. But before exploring this, I had a question: which version should I use?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>